Guide to the Annise Parker Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Annise Parker Papers
1991-2005
2008-004
Parker, Annise
9.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection is housed in 9 boxes and arranged in 7 series. Annise Parker’s papers document her campaigns for elected office in the City of Houston from: City Council Race-Defeated-1991; City Council Race-Defeated-1995; City Council Race-Won-1997; City Council Race-Won-2001; City Controller Race-Won-2003; and City Controller Race-Won-2005.
Biographical Information:
Annise Parker was born and reared in Houston’s Spring Branch area. Annise’s mother worked as a bookkeeper, and her father worked for the Red Cross. The family moved to the U. S. Army base in Mannheim, Germany for two years when Annise was 15. Afterwards, she attended Rice University in 1974 on a National Merit Scholarship and worked several jobs to pay for her room and board. She graduated in 1978, beginning a 20-year career in the oil and gas industry – 18 of them at Houston’s Mosbacher Energy.
Following this period, Annise moved into public service in 1997, as the first openly gay City Council Member to be elected in Houston, Texas. She and her life partner, Kathy Hubbard, have been together since 1990, and they have two adopted children. From 1997 to 2003, Parker held a seat on Houston’s City Council, and then served as the City Controller of Houston for six years. Annise Parker was elected mayor of Houston on December 12, 2009.
In addition to her work in city politics, Parker has been the subject and author of numerous newspaper and magazine articles across the country. Parker is very active in the GLBT Community and the Houston community as a whole. She serves on various governing bodies such as the Board of Directors of the Holocaust Museum Houston and Girls Inc. and the Advisory Boards of the Houston Zoo, the Montrose Counseling Center, Bering Omega Community Services, and Trees for Houston.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Fliers (printed matter); Photographs; Typescripts; Videocassettes
Personal Name:
Parker, Annise
Topical Term:
City council members -- Texas -- Houston; Gay politicians; Mayors -- Texas -- Houston; Political campaigns -- Texas -- Houston; Politicians; Women city council members -- Texas -- Houston; Women mayors -- Texas -- Houston; Women politicians
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
ROADWomen Records (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=504)
Scope and Contents
This collection is housed in 9 boxes and arranged in 7 series. Annise Parker’s papers document her campaigns for elected office in the City of Houston from: City Council Race-Defeated-1991; City Council Race-Defeated-1995; City Council Race-Won-1997; City Council Race-Won-2001; City Controller Race-Won-2003; and City Controller Race-Won-2005. Material formats within these series range from newspaper clippings and video recordings to correspondence and typescript. A 7th series includes a single folder containing programs, press clippings, invitations, and other materials related to Parker's 2009 mayoral election that have been collected and added to the collection.
Detailed List of Contents
- City Council Race-Defeated, 1991
  - Campaign Finance Report (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Video-Annise Parker for City Council, District C (Box 1, Folder 4)
- City Council Race-Defeated, 1995
  - Candidate Support Material (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Promotional Material (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interview Script (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph- Annise Parker, headshot (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 10)
- City Council Race-Won, 1997
  - Ballot Paper (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campaign consulting services- Snyder, Giles (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Finance Report (Box 1, Folder 14-17)
  - Campaign Fundraising & Consulting Services-Miller Group (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Campaign Promotional Material (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Campaign Recap, by Vanessa Edwards-Foster (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Campaign Treasurer Appointments (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tape- Annise Parker City Council,KCOH-1430 (AM), 11/21/97 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - City Issues/Policy (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Congratulatory Notes (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Corporate Solicitation List (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence; Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Database Information and Design (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Donor Roster (pre 1997) (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - E-mail Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Events (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Finance Committee Meetings (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Fitch, Don-Opponent Information (Box 1, Folder 35-37)
  - Fundraising Letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Election Votes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hernandez, Rafael-Opponent Information (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - House Party Planning (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Houston AIDS Walk-Team Information (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Houston Gay and Lesbian Chamber of Commerce Membership Roster (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Invitation (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Media Advertising Questions (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Media; Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Merchant Services Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Navarro, Yolanda-Opponent Information (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Neosoft (Sponsor) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Opponents; Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Personal Financial Disclosures (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Petition for Place on Election Ballot (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Positively Parker Campaign Volunteer Forms (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Positively Parker Volunteer Guide (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Press Release (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Scenic Conservation Survey (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Various Mailing Lists (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Video- Rindy Media, Annise Parker “Parade”, AP-03, 11/19/97 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Video-Annise Parker, by Scottie Scott, 11/4/97 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Video-Parker Elected, 12/6/97-KTRK-TC (Ch.13) 10pm; KRIV-TV (Ch.26) 9pm, 12/7/97 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Video-Annise Parker-City Council Race, KRIV-TV (Ch.26) 9pm; KTRK-TV (Ch.13) 10pm, 11/4/97 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Video-Rindy Media, Annise Parker for Houston City Council, “Best Qualified”, “Parade” (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Video-Rindy Media, Annise Parker, AP97-1 “Best Qualified”, 10/20/97 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Scrapbook (Binder) (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook (Binder) (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Campaign Finance Reports (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Campaign Promotional Material (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - City Council Agenda (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gay and Lesbian Committee Business Seminar (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Inaugural Invitation (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Internal Documents (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Questionnaires (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Voter’s Survey (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Video-Anisse Parker-File Tape, 1/2/98 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Video-Houston City Council, 1/2/98 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Video-Houston City Council, 1/6/98 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Video-Parker City Council Race (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Video-Rindy Miller Media-“Parker” (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Binder) (Box 5, Item 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Binder) (Box 5, Item 2)
- City Council Race-Won, 2001
  - Campaign Management Forms (Binder) (Box 5, Item 3)
  - Official Correspondence (Binder) (Box 5, Item 4)
  - Campaign Expenses (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Campaign Finance Report (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Campaign Kickoff Party (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Publicity (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Website Planning (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Direct Mail Service Agreement (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Events (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - General Ballot Filing Fees (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Membership Dues (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Press Release (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Printed Publicity (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Questionnaires (Box 6, Folder 17)
- City Controller Race-Won, 2003
  - Ballot Application (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Campaign Corps (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Campaign Ephemera (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Campaign Financial Report (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
  - Campaign Insurance Policy (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Campaign Office Lease Agreement (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Campaign Plan, 2/1/2003 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Campaign Tax Filing (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Campaign Treasurer Appointment (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Candidate Questionnaires (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Houston Mayoral Run-off Election Survey (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - IN-kind Campaign Donation (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Inauguration Invitation (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Jones, Steve-Opponent Information (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Lee, Mark-Opponent Information (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Meeting Notes (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Political Consultant Contracts (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Potential Voter’s Survey, February 2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Potential Voter’s Survey, March 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Potential Voter’s Survey, October 2003 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Press Release (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Printed Publicity Material (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Tatro, Bruce-Opponent Information (Box 7, Folder 8-12)
  - Tatro, Bruce-Opponent Information (Background Report Volume I) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Tatro, Bruce-Opponent Information (Background Report Volume II) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tatro, Bruce-Opponent Information (Background Report Volume III) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Texas Ethics Commission Investigation (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Video-Rindy Miller Media-“Fiscal Watchdog” (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Confidential Self-Research, Avanti Intl. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Parker, Annise-Self-Research Study (Volume I) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Parker, Annise-Self-Research Study (Volume II) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Parker, Annise-Self-Research Study (Volume III) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Parker, Annise-Self-Research Study (Volume IV) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Parker, Annise-Self-Research Study (Volume V) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Video-Annise Parker Controller Race (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Video-Channel 2 News (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Video-Parker 10/10 Debate (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Video-Steve Jones Commercial (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Video-The Municipal Channel-“Controller’s Office/Council” (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Volunteer Information (Box 9, Folder 6)
- City Controller Race-Won, 2005
  - Campaign Consulting (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Expenditures (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Finance Report (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
  - House Parties (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Victory Fund (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Mayoral Race-Won, 2010
  - Inauguration program, press clippings, invitations, and other materials, 2010-2011 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    These materials have been collected and added to the collection.